Lowell Thomas Film Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 10. New Guinea, 1942-1977; 444 cans
  - New Guinea, 1957; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 3176)
    The ground, feet, group of natives, man holding a large straw basket, beads strung across trees, man wearing a large feather head piece, group, men setting up a camera, man fixing feather head piece, giant idol mask/body pieces, woman fixing parts of other man's head piece/jewelry, natives, group of natives in a semi circle, one wearing idol mask, other wearing feather head piece, man holding two staffs, dancing/ceremony, man in feather head piece, man carrying congas, man standing up staff for man with head piece, natives carrying staffs above heads, some natives and children standing around, man standing on a stage in front of fabrics and decorations, others join, woman walking, people behind her carrying palms, moving sticks/palms to build a hut, inside of the hut, natives fixing palms, group of natives, fixing palms.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - High Adventure New Guinea, 1957; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 3177)
    Airplane taking off. People standing outside of their home. Children in a gorup. People rowing. Director: Robinson.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - New Guinea Takes, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 3178)
    Clapboard "Scene 1002, take 3," Two boys sitting down in a forest like area, clapboard "Scene 1002, take 5," Clapboard "Scene 1005, take 4," the boys get up and begin to walk forward, someone examines something on the ground with a small pick like tool, said person then places what looks like a rock in a box, clapboard "Scene 1011, take 1," clapboard "scene 1019, take 1," clapboard "Scene 1030, take 1," a man sitting at a table outside, the two boys join him and it seems like the converse, closeup on one of the children, snakes on the ground, the front of a building; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - New Guinea, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 3179)
    Clapboard "Scene 536, take 1," a kid sits on the ground with toys around, a woman and the kid move stuff between a plane and a tent, clapboard "Scene 528, take 1," clapboard "Scene 531, take 1," the kid picks up something from the ground, Clapboard "Scene 545, take 1," closeup of Lowell Thomas Jr., clapboard "Scene 547, take 1," closeup of an old man with large goggles looking around, the kid stands next to what appears to be a baby donkey, clapboard "Scene 83, take 1,"; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - New Guinea, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 3180)
    Someone looking over the side of a boat, the initial boat encounters yet another boat, people on the boats look at each other, closeup of the bottom of the boat going through the water; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Odyssey, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 3181)
    The moon moves across the sky, starting in the middle of the frame.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - L Thomas High Adventure Natives, 1958; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 3182)
    Closeup of some guy with an interesting outfit, Lowell Thomas outside with natives, closeup on one of the native men, two people standing next to each other; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - New Guinea, 1954; linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 3183)
    Five people in tribal paint carrying sticks, a large crowd of natives with sticks, a closeup on the crowd with three people in the foreground, natives with sticks running, empty landscape, people in a field, people carrying packs through a field with tall plants, a long line of people, a closeup on a man walking, a man in headdress and face paint with a spear, a crowd of people with spears hiding in tall plants, legs and bare feet in a field, a big crowd of people in tribal garb.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
- 11. Russia, 1949-1961; 107 cans
  - Russia, 300 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 518)
    Multiple takes of a narrator recording lines about Christmas in Jerusalem, as well as a trade school opened by American Monsignor John Nolan.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Int. Plane, New Bldgs + Walkers in May, Lenengrad Garden, Baikal, K. Airport, Int. Plane, Plane Int., Tomb C4, Peterhof, Khabarosk, Girl on Trapeze, Tashkent - INTK, Red SQ, IRKVT2, 1949; 173 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 519)
    Shots of different areas in Leningrad. Cut to people sitting in the park and walking down the street.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Russia sound effects, 103 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 520)
    A fast paced song is played by a symphony.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Irkutsk - Park, River, Street, Tourists, 287 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 521)
    "Wild Sound #1," used on park bench. Audio of background noises at a park.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - In Boat on Lake Baikal B.G. Noise and Music (Russia) R 16, 17, 18, 317 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 522)
    On the audio track you can hear background noise of people talking and beeping noise. You can hear someone saying, "hi dear, how are you this morning?" You can hear a car door closing, you hear people laughing and music playing playing. You also hear a women asking about taking pictures and you also hear a man talks about tourist unloading and getting ready for a cruise.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Russia chorus, 323 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 523)
    On the audio track you can hear different musicals of people singing.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Russia sound effects, 234 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 524)
    The entire track is of classical music; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Russia sound effects, 14 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 525)
    There was no audio; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Russia chorus, 234 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 526)
    We hear audio of a choir singing. A woman introduces the next song. The choir then sing two more songs accompanied by an accordion.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Siberia, 1950; 389 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 527)
    Lowell Thomas is shown speaking with two women in a square of Moscow. People are walking around and children are playing together and showing their toys to the camera. Along a river, scenic views of the buildings are displayed and the film ends with 2 men playing instruments on a stage.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Russia sound effects, 255 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 528)
    Background noise. New Guinea natives talking to each other. We can hear a man singing in the distance. Cut to a man recording audio of children laughing.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - LT in Airport (no sound) People Walking in Streets, 1949; 132 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 529)
    Lowell Thomas greets passengers as they wait to enter an airplane. He has them smile for the camera. Cut to footage of citizens walking around Moscow.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Russia, 199 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 530)
    Lowell Thomas is shown at an airport runaway speaking with a man among a crowd of people gathered around the plane. The rest of the film shows some sort of minerals in a cave/mine.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Khabarovsk, 1950; 43 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 531)
    A crowd of people gather around a train stop.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - AS10 (B) Taskent Park, 92 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 532)
    People are going about their daily business. A car drives by, people are walking through the park, children are playing, and a man is reading on a bench.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Russia scenes, 413 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 533)
    Much of the film shows people at the beach where several boats are on the water, people play volleyball and boys ride their bikes into the water. The rest of the film shows people walking around on the street.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Russian life, 378 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 534)
    On the audio track you can hear background noise pf transportation and beeping noise. You can hear someone talking about last sequence shot women sweeping the street. You can also hear people saying different locations of where they are going to shoot. They also mentioned the last shot they took of golden bridge with lion heads with people rowing under it and that their next shot is of the beach and then of Peter and Paul fortress; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Moscow, 264 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 535)
    Faint audio of people talking.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Tourist in Guide Voice, Neusky Prospect Leningrad, 189 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 536)
    On the audio track you can hear someone mentioning an interview and the last shot they took was of a statue. You can hear background noises of transportation and of people talking. You also hear a man mentioning something about a man not speaking English and mentioning the last shot he took was of girls crossing the street. You can also hear people talking and a man talking in another language and you hear music playing.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Russia changing guard, 226 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 537)
    On the audio track you can hear background noise of people talking, beeping noise, transportation, a clock dinging, and the sound of people walking.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Irkutsk street scenes (trolley, cars), 367 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 538)
    On the audio track you can hear background noise of transportation, a horse walking and people talking. You can hear a man saying that he forgot to turn the tape off and you also hear other people talking in a different language.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Russia R.I MUS Parade Music (at airport), Moscow Music, Classical Music for Beg. Titles, Russia Prod. TKA I (Parade) over Beg. Titles, Prod. tkB Russia, Eastern Music 3rd Beg. Titles, Village Russian String Music, Dessert Climate Music, Red Square Music, Festive Russian Music, Nursery Singing Children, Parade Music 2d Beg. Titles, Russian Accord, 331 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 539)
    On the film you can hear different type of music playing, different instruments, different singers, and you hear children singing.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color, N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - 115 Take off Festive Music 90-129 R-1, MUS B; Irkutsk Street "Chicago of Siberia" 107 398-428 Russian Mood Music Russia R-1 MUS; 102. 77-102 Russian Mood Music Russia R-1 MUS; Bratskdam Russian Parade Music 106. 327-360 Russia R-1 MUS; Prod TK B Russia 16. Students Circus Music; (University) Russian String Orchestra 108. 429-461 Russian R-1 MUS; Russia Prod-TK B 13. Festive Music Beg Titles; Russia 9. Uzbek Music Prod Trk A, 217 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 540)
    On the audio track you can hear different music and different instruments being played.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Poss Farm 7, Voice 23, 3 NTC, 4, 13, 339 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 541)
    On the audio track you can hear different music and different music being played.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Siberia, 1950; 358 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 542)
    The film showed people on a about drinking, it showed people at vegetable market, it showed a man on a donkey, and it showed a forested area. The film showed children with flowers in their hands, it showed people walking around, it showed Lowell Thomas, it showed a boat sailing to dock and it showed people going on the boat. The film showed a group of people standing by a statue and it showed a bus stopping and letting people off it. The film also showed a river mountains and flowers.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Siberia, 1950; 350 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 543)
    The film showed men fishing, it showed a boat, it showed Lowell Thomas and other people outside at a airport talking. The film showed a forested area, it showed cows, chicken, and goats, it showed a little girl carrying a bucket. The film showed people buying and selling bread, it showed buildings and houses, it showed a man sawing wood. The film also showed cars, trucks and buses.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Leningrad-Nevsky Prospect, Anchorage Airport Outs, 102 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 544)
    On the audio track you can hear transportation passing by, you can hear beeping noise and people talking in the background. You can hear a man say, "by the way do you know anyone that you would like to send to Siberia? There is always room for more." You also hear him talk about the different locations like Alaska and Russia, he talks about distance, miles and how many flights you would have to take to get to Siberia.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - LT i Simplot, 1969; 224 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 545)
    The film showed Lowell Thomas sitting on a bench talking to another man.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - T. Simplet Interview, 327 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 546)
    Lowell Thomas narrates from an airport in Alaska. He documents the first time passengers have ever flown from North America to Siberia. Before the plane takes off Lowell interviews a man. The two men stray off topic and spend a long time discussing the economic problems of Siberia.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Russia, 161 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 547)
    Background audio of airplanes taking off.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Alaska Aerial Shot Rehrints, Russian Tourists Lenin Wall, 242 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 548)
    An Alaska plane is shown taking off from the runaway and then aerial views of snow-capped mountains are played. At the end a photographer is trying to get a large group of people together for a picture.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - LT - Sync, 319 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 549)
    Audio of Lowell Thomas interviewing a Siberian woman. She explains that she is from an area that is technically not considered Siberia. Lowell Thomas speaks to us from outside of the Hermitage Museum. Next, he speaks to us from the main square in Leningrad. He does many takes of this. Lowell Thomas interviews passerby's in Leningrad.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Russia, 1950; 263 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 551)
    Aerial shot of snow-covered mountains. Lowell Thomas interviews three Russian women in Leningrad Square. We watch Russian performers dance and act on a stage. Cut to men and women walking around the streets of Leningrad. Nature shots of the woods. Shots of Moscow architecture.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Siberia, 1950; 267 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 552)
    Lowell Thomas speaks to the camera from in front of an airplane. Shots of Siberia. Cut to Lowell Thomas interviewing a man on a park bench. Lowell Thomas interviews citizens in front of a large fountain in Siberia.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Siberia, 23 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 553)
    Audio of Lowell Thomas talking about Leningrad, "The Hero City." It has been rebuilt and is now "more glorious than ever."; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - audience, Rhinos, Laughing, Russia Applause, Nepal Mine Outs, Rhino's?, Nepal: Mime Outs, 137 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 554)
    The audio played animal sounds, applause noise, and a person singing with musical instruments playing.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Heavy Traffic, Light street noise, 65 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 555)
    The audio plays sounds from the street. People's footsteps, people talking, and cars passing by.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Russia outs, 1949; 16 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 556)
    a man speaks to a people speaking at dinner tables; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Russia outs, 1949; 16 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 557)
    A man tells a few passive jokes that people laugh along to; Format: 16mm; Picture:; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Red Square Changing Guard, 320 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 558)
    Background noise. Bells ring. Voice: 'Crowd noises in Red Square, Moscow." Lowell Thomas comments on the Russian traditional costumes. We hear the passing of the guards at Lenin's tomb.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Russia Selected Music, 438 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 559)
    Title on leader: "Russia - Selected Music." An orchestra performs four or five traditional Russian songs.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - School children and election day in Tashkent with american voices BG, 462 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 560)
    Audio: "Wild sounds of schoolchildren." We hear children playing in the background and birds chirping.; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Siberia, 1949; 426 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 574)
    The film showed people walking around in different directions, it showed the statue of a canon, it showed buildings, it showed vehicles going by, it showed people in an auditorium and it showed people performing on stage.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Siberia, 80 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 561)
    The film showed a lot of people sitting in an auditorium clapping and it showed people performing and playing instruments.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Siberia, 1949; 163 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 562)
    Clips of Russian circus performers.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Siberia, 1949; 254 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 563)
    The film showed Lowell Thomas sitting on a bench talking to another man. It also showed a group of men and women on stage dancing.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Siberia 6/24/70, 1950; 170 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 564)
    The film showed a man and a woman dancing with men behind them playing instruments and it showed a choir of men and women singing and it a man playing an accordion.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Siberia, 1950; 279 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 565)
    The film showed buildings, it showed cars, it showed people walking outside and it showed people walking inside a building. The film showed people at the beach, it showed Lowell Thomas talking a man in the streets and it showed people dancing and playing instruments.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Leningrad-Nevsky Prospect, Simpeot, 34 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 566)
    Lowell Thomas speaking to the camera in front of the Hermitage Museum.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Leningrad-Nevsky Prospect, Simpeot, 35 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 567)
    Lowell Thomas speaking about the Hermitage Museum.; Format: 16mm; Picture:; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Leningrad-Nevsky Prospect, Simpeot, 179 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 568)
    Lowell Thomas having a conversation with another man.; Format: 16mm; Picture:; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Montay and Music, 155 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 569)
    Footage of toddlers playing together outside. Cut to Lowell Thomas in front of an airplane, speaking to the camera. Close up of the Kremlin. We see people walking around Red Square. Title on screen: "The Other Side of Serbia."; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Montay and Music, 40 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 570)
    Sounds of german music and people singing; Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Siberia, 1950; 134 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 571)
    Music is being played with distinct singing and drum playing; Format: 16mm; Picture:; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Siberia, 1950; 18 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 572)
    A very short look at a band playing music; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Siberia, 1950; 72 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 573)
    Lowell Thomas speaks with a man and asks him what the host country he is in would look like if it adopted a different political system; Format: 16mm; Picture:; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Loops - title music, kids laugh, red sq talking, music, birds & pigs, 36 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 975)
    Instrumental title music (Sounds like an action scene- driving sixteenth notes with the fourth accented and brass melody over it), sheep bleeting, child laughing, Lowell Thomas saying "so long", combinations of crowd's voices/motor/birds/sheep, hearty chorus singing, and more instrumental title music (best way to descsribe this one is a sort of funky suspenseful jazz, but there is probably a better way); Format: 16mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - 1: CUE 29 TAIL TRIM, 2: IBM OFFICE, 3: CHORUS TRIM: PROD TK B RUSSIA: MINISKIRT BIT MUSIC CHORUS OF SINGERS, 4: ZODIAK, 5: HOUSE TRIM: 6 PRODA CIRCUS MUSIC TRK: HORSES OP, 6: IBM, 7: LiBIKAL TRIM, linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 984)
    On the audio track you can hear singing and instrument being played.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color, N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Optical, Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Baikal outs, 190 linear feet 1 400ft (16mm) (Can 1000)
    Outtakes. Scenes includes people walking, an industrial city, a boat, and a red flag with hammer and sickle.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Russia, 613 linear feet 1 1200ft (16mm) (Can 1354)
    Lowell Thomas narrates as Charles Willis, founder of Alaska Airlines, leads the first commercial flight of 130 passengers from North America to Siberia. It includes small segments of interviews with some passengers, as well as background types of noises, such as the rumbling of a plane taking off, the clip-clop of heels on pavement, and people talking.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color, Black & White; Audio: Optical, Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Russia, 744 linear feet 1 1200ft (16mm) (Can 1355)
    Rumble, children talking, polka/ accordian music, more rumbling and talking, bells, and more rumbling and talking.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical, Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Russia sound effects, 1950; 823 linear feet 1 1200ft (16mm) (Can 1356)